Xavier Maso

security, software, and cryptography engineer

(+33) 621 · 822 · 328 \diamond xav.maso@gmail.com www.xaviermaso.com

Skills

Security	Script ☆☆☆	9	Reverse Engineering		g E	Exploitation		Pentesting		
Software development										
•	rthon	Bash ☆☆☆☆★				I x86 ☆★★	Ru	ıby AA		script <mark>☆☆☆</mark>
Rust	Elm-Lar		aml A ★★	Nix ☆☆☆		Has ☆☆ ₁	kell ☆★★	Ja ☆ ☆₁	va	Latex

Systems administration

Linux: NixOS, Ubuntu, Debian, Raspbian, Fedora.

Continuous integration: Ansible, Docker, Jenkins, Travis, Capistrano.

Soft skills

Team management: implement the environment which allows to develop the products and achieve goals.

Used to Agile methodology, especially Scrum, and Lean approaches. Pair, and mob programming. TDD practice.

Speaker: animation and presentation about a product, a project or to share experiences.

Interpersonal: listening and understanding individuals to facilitate interactions within a group.

Professional experience

Oracle NetSuite

November 2021 - Today

Remote

Senior Application Security Engineer

The Product Security Team assits development teams during the lifecycle of the different software components building NetSuite solutions.

Tweag

May 2021 - September 2021

Open Source Fellow

Remote

Tweag is a French software innovation lab running a fellowship program for those eager to contribute to open source projects.

- · Worked on fuzzing nix, the declarative package manager.
- · Target definition and priorization; Write fuzzers; Explore using sanitizers; Run small experimental fuzzing sessions.
- · Integrate to OSS-fuzz.

Arizona State University (ASU)

Research apprenticeship on binary analysis

April 2019 – September 2021 Phoenix. United States of America

ASU's Security Engineering for Future Computing (SEFCOM) laboratory is a world-class cybersecurity research lab carrying out cutting-edge academic research.

- · Design, implement, and evaluate a new, fast static binary analysis technique.
- · Study state-of-the art: symbolic and concolic execution, fuzzing, automated exploit generation.
- · Contribute to angr, the open-source binary analysis framework.
- · Guest lecturer for CSE545 Software Security (Fall 2020): presentation, and live examples on using angr to implement a static binary analysis technique.

Mozilla Corporation

May 2018 - August 2018

Web security intern, Scanning modern web applications with OWASP ZAP

London, United Kingdom

The Firefox Operations Security team protects the core services and release engineering infrastructures Mozilla relies on to build, ship and run Firefox.

OWASP ZAP is a free and open-sourced security tools to help automatically find security vulnerabilities in web applications.

- · Research and development in Javascript and the DOM API: keep track of events and interactions happening in a webpage. Released the @zaproxy/front-end-tracker library on npm.
- · Development of a ZAP add-on to create a framework for pentesters to run security scripts directly in the browser.
- · Research on modern web applications (Single Page Applications) vulnerabilities.
- · Part of a distributed team and contributing to an open-source community.

Orange Application for Business

June 2017 - August 2017

System administrator, Securing workstations

Bordeaux, France

OAB is a subsidiary of Orange S.A developing and hosting services for businesses.

Integrated to an operations team of four, my mission was to secure their Linux workstations.

- · System administration: Arch, Ubuntu, Debian.
- · Define and apply good security practices for laptops and mobile devices.
- · Development: ansible roles, audit-ssh-client-config script.
- · Research: securing the boot process (anti-evil maid), NixOS, Public Key Infrastructures.
- · Training and communication about the security practices: write documentation, create tutorials, run workshops.

RedShield Security Ltd

January 2015 - April 2016

Software engineer

Wellington, New Zealand

Shielding-with-a-service company providing a web application firewall, vulnerability scanner and analyzer to assist IT departments ensure the security of their systems.

- · Development in Ruby and Javascript; Debugging, and automate testing.
- · Configuration of production and CI servers (Jenkins).
- · Security: offensive, secure development, incident response.

CER SNCF

June 2012 - Oct 2014

Full-stack developer

Bordeaux, France

Distributed all over the Aquitaine and Poitou Charentes French regions, the CER (for Committee of Regionnal Establishment) provides services to SNCF's workers.

Missions

· Web development, information system administration and maintenance, automation.

- · IT service management: needs analysis; goals, processes, and tasks definition; listing of skills and resources to prioritize our work.
- · Help in recruitment for IT service: define required skills, and mission scopes; Interview candidates.

Project, subject of my master thesis

- · Build a website dedicated to SNCF's employees: tasks and planning definition, resources and skills affectation to provide this new service within six months with a three person team.
- \cdot Communication and product launching: define and reach targets, follow the adoption and usage of the product.
- · Integration within the existing information system: shared databases services, web server deployment.
- · Server on Ubuntu 14.04, database is PostgreSQL, Nginx and Unicorn as web stack.
- · Application built with Ruby-On-Rails, Slim, SASS and CoffeeScript. RSpec and Capybara for testing and QA.

Education

University of Bordeaux

2016 - 2019

College of Sciences and Technologies

Bordeaux, France

- · One year of refresher training in Mathematics.
- · Master Mathematics and Applications: Cryptology and IT Security.

Ingésup (www.ingesup.com)

2009 - 2014

Information System Expert

Bordeaux, France

Five year of university studies in computer information technologies (speciality in Development).

- Member of the security lab: research and learning about exploitation and penetration testing.
- · Member of the games lab: participation in video game development contests.

Lycée La Boétie, Academy of Bordeaux

2005 - 2009

French Baccalauréat in Sciences (speciality in Mathematics), with honors.

Projects

Personal dedicated servers

2014 - Today

 $server\ administration$

Co-owner of dedicated servers, used to manage self-hosted services such as Gogits, NextCloud, Selfoss, etc. as well as diverse websites. Running on Debian systems, using Ansible for reproducibility and automation, and Docker containers for modularity and isolation.

xaviermaso.com 2015 - Today

web development

My personal website. Front-end written in Elm, back-end powered by ExpressJS.

Sources on Github: github.com/Pamplemousse/xaviermaso.com.

DjangoGirls Bordeaux

2016 - 2019

 $non ext{-}profit$

Non-profit community that empowers and helps women get involved with programming. Organization and coaching for DjangoGirls events, and recurring meetups. Teaching programming basics using Python.

There are more: abandonned projects, dirty hacks that I am not proud of anymore... Have a look on my website: xaviermaso.com/projects.

Hobbies

Challenges	Reading	Sports
microcorruption, root-me	sciences, economy, politics,	muay thai, diving (PADI AOW)
HackTheBox	psychology, and sociology	former judoka, football and handball player